# **Kush Patel**

kushpatel0703@gmail.com | (630) 523-2190 | LinkedIn: kpatel0703 | Github: kushpatel0703 6N381 Acacia Lane, Medinah, IL 60157

### **OBJECTIVE**

A curious learner and dedicated team member with 3 years of industry software engineering experience looking for a fast-paced, progressive company to utilize my customer oriented product skills while continuing to develop my engineering skillset.

#### EXPERIENCE

**Amazon** Seattle, WA

Software Development Engineer

April 2020 - Present

- Contributed to real time data processing platform for all Amazon advertising traffic
- Designed new process which reduced the effort to on-board a new marketplace from 6 to 0 developer days
- Interacted with data consumers to prioritize requested feature development and data quality investigations
- o Participated in on-call rotation to maintain stability and accessibility of entire AWS data processing fleet
- Created traffic simulation tool in Python which reduced testing effort for new releases and peak traffic days by 50%

LendingHome

San Francisco, CA May 2019 - Aug 2019

Software Engineering Intern

- · Automated the loan origination process platform using Ruby on Rails in an agile environment
- Developed document based data-capture methods to simplify and expedite the loan process for consumers
- o Interfaced with PostgreSQL database and GraphQL to access and modify real-time production loan data
- Practiced test driven development principles by utilizing RSpec as a test framework tool

Urbana, IL State Farm

Data Engineering Intern

Jan 2019 - May 2019

- o Built a smart reporting module to report errors from the Hadoop Network to various teams based on prior error data
- Utilized SQL to analyze customer behavior data to improve State Farm services by displaying to a Django dashboard
- Saved an estimated 160 analyst hours per year through automation and optimizations

**Zebra Technologies** 

Lincolnshire, IL

Firmware Engineering Intern

May 2018 - Aug 2018

- o Integrated sensors to create a more accurate alert system for detecting media status on Zebra Printers
- Developed an algorithm to determine media status threshold for the printer's modified alert system
- Built an analytical framework within the printer firmware to measure and collect printer metadata using C++

#### **Zebra Technologies**

Lincolnshire, IL

Advanced Development Intern

May 2017 - Aug 2017

- Improved print quality testing results by automating image analytics through Python and Shell scripting
- Collected environmental printer data using external sensors integrated in Python and stored in a PostgreSQL database
- o Designed a data analytics dashboard using Django, HTML, and CSS to display data stored in an AWS Database

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages & Frameworks: Python, Ruby, Java, Scala, C, C++, SQL, Shell Scripting, Rails, Django, Spark, Flask
- Tools: AWS, Git, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Hadoop, Jira, RSpec, Linux

## **EDUCATION**

#### University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign

Urbana, IL Dec 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Relevant Coursework: Distributed Systems, OS Development, Algorithms and Models of Computation, Artificial Intelligence, Data Structures in C++, Database Systems, Communication Networks, Discrete Structures, Probability Principles

#### **PROJECTS**

ByteOS: Developed a Posix-based kernel from scratch in C and x86 Assembly which implemented paging, system calls, scheduling, file systems, device drivers, and multiple terminals

Media Search Engine: Created a Python and Django based web application to display information about a TV show or movie on an interactive UI and generate recommendations based on genre tag analysis